First countable and uncountable nouns.
第一个可数名词和不可数名词。
Let's just be very clear on these.
让我们非常清楚这些。
A noun can be a physical thing an object or something more abstract something we cannot touch.
名词可以是物理的事物或物体，也可以是我们无法触及的更抽象的事物。
It is in many cases the uncountable things that we cannot touch and the things we can touch are countable.
在许多情况下，我们无法触摸的不可数的东西，我们可以触摸的东西是可数的。
But let's not say that's a rule because there are lots of examples in which that's not true.
但我们不要说这是一个规则，因为有很多例子表明这是不正确的。
And we'll just look at a couple.
我们只看一对。
So for example chairs.
例如椅子。
Well we can say one chair two chairs three chairs OK one chair because there is one we say chair and
好吧，我们可以说一把椅子 两把椅子 三把椅子 OK 一把椅子，因为我们说椅子和
then because there's more than one we say chairs.
然后因为有不止一个我们说椅子。
We had an.
我们有一个。
This one.
这个。
One person two people we can count one two three cups one cup two cups ideas cookies eyes eyes.
一个人两个人我们可以数一二三杯一杯两杯创意饼干眼睛眼睛。
Push one push Two pushes.
一推两推。
OK.
好的。
Builders discoveries stories.
建设者发现故事。
A story two stories.
一个故事两个故事。
Fish.
鱼。
One fish two fish.
一鱼二鱼。
Sometimes it doesn't change.
有时它不会改变。
Children.
孩子们。
One child.
一个小孩。
Two children.
两个孩子。
Eggs an egg.
鸡蛋一个鸡蛋。
Two eggs grains.
两个鸡蛋粒。
One grain two grains.
一粒两粒。
Very very small boats.
非常非常小的船。
Boats.
船。
A boat.
一条船。
Two boats.
两艘船。
But I should be very very clear.
但我应该非常非常清楚。
Sometimes things that are often countable can be uncountable.
有时，通常可数的事物可能是不可数的。
That means you cannot count them for example.
这意味着您无法计算它们。
Discovery can be a more general idea when something is a more general idea.
当某事是一个更普遍的想法时，发现可以是一个更普遍的想法。
It's often uncountable so we can have a discovery to discoveries.
它通常是不可数的，因此我们可以对发现进行发现。
But we can just say for example.
但我们可以举个例子。
Discovery is the very beginning of a new trend.
发现是新趋势的开始。
Discovery is the beginning of a new trend that is not accountable discovery.
发现是一种新趋势的开始，它不是负责任的发现。
That is an uncountable discovery.
这是一个不可数的发现。
That's a general idea.
这是一个普遍的想法。
OK now I want to just mention one thing very quickly when we're talking about something generally speaking
好的，当我们谈论一般性的事情时，我只想快速提及一件事
and it's a countable thing.
这是一个可数的事情。
Let's use the plural form.
让我们使用复数形式。
Let's use the plural form the reason we use the plural form is because we could be talking about any
让我们使用复数形式我们使用复数形式的原因是因为我们可以谈论任何
one of those things.
其中之一。
For example you should say I like dogs not I like dog.
例如，你应该说我喜欢狗而不是我喜欢狗。
Children are wonderful.
孩子们很棒。
We're using the plural form.
我们使用复数形式。
Not one child but children.
不是一个孩子，而是孩子。
Children.
孩子们。
So we just have to be careful about that.
所以我们只需要注意这一点。
And again it can be a little bit more complicated.
再一次，它可能会更复杂一些。
For example we would say I like pizza.
例如，我们会说我喜欢披萨。
I like pizza.
我喜欢披萨。
But then if we say pizza in that way we're actually saying an uncountable thing an uncountable thing.
但是如果我们这样说披萨，我们实际上是在说一个不可数的东西，一个不可数的东西。
So sometimes nouns that we can count one pizza two pizzas also become uncountable.
所以有时我们可以数一个披萨两个披萨的名词也变得不可数。
If we're talking about a general idea that thing for example pizza we often use that for different kinds
如果我们谈论的是一个总体概念，例如比萨饼，我们经常将其用于不同种类
of food.
的食物。
OK so uncountable things are things we generally cannot count.
好的，所以不可数的东西是我们通常无法计算的东西。
And again there are examples when it can be both.
还有一些例子可以两者兼而有之。
For example you could say one time two times one time I went to Canada the second time I went to Germany.
例如，您可以说一次两次，一次我去加拿大，第二次去德国。 但时间的概念是不可数的希望。
Can you say one hope.
你能说一个希望吗。
Oh I suppose but it's Yeah.
哦，我想，但它是的。
Generally uncountable ambition ambition.
雄心壮志一般不可数。
Milk.
牛奶。
You can't count a liquid.
你不能凑不是液体。
OK liquids are another one.
OK液体是另一种。
Experience experience very similar to discovery.
体验体验非常类似于发现。
If we make this discovery we can say many experiences but we're then talking about each one.
如果我们做出这个发现，我们可以说很多经验，但我们是在谈论每一个。
But if we're talking about the general idea of experience then we can't make it a plural we can't count
但是，如果我们谈论的是经验的一般概念，那么我们就不能把它变成复数，我们不能数
it.
它。
Orange juice is another liquid teamwork Love.
橙汁是另一种液体团队合作的爱。
Love is an idea.
爱是一个想法。
Generally not countable sadness and emotion generally not countable Joy beauty.
一般不可数悲伤和情绪一般不可数喜悦美丽。
So we're talking about a lot of a lot of concepts a lot of concepts over here general ideas.
所以我们在这里谈论很多很多概念很多概念。
So when we have these general ideas we're putting them in the uncountable form we're considering them
所以当我们有这些一般的想法时，我们把它们放在不可数的形式中，我们正在考虑它们
uncountable and just to be very very clear.
不可数，只是要非常非常清楚。
You can often make these countable as well because you could say I'd like to have an orange juice.
您通常也可以使这些可数，因为您可以说我想喝橙汁。
If we're talking about a specific one that's ok it's ok but most often if we say I like orange juice
如果我们谈论的是一个特定的，那没关系，但大多数情况下，如果我们说我喜欢橙汁
we're using the uncountable version or form of orange juice.
我们使用的是不可数版本或形式的橙汁。
OK if we say experience is very important.
好吧，如果我们说经验非常重要。
We're not talking about specific experiences that we can count.
我们不是在谈论我们可以计算的具体经验。
We're talking about the idea the concept of experience in which case we should use the uncountable form
我们谈论的是经验的概念，在这种情况下我们应该使用不可数形式
uncountable.
不可数。
All right.
好的。
I hope that's clear.
我希望这很清楚。
I wanted to just make that very very clear before we get started with examples of each different quantifying.
在我们开始使用每种不同量化的示例之前，我想非常清楚地说明这一点。